Michael Sanford

Senior IT Administrator / NOC Manager / Director of IT - Northwest Cascade Inc

Auburn, WA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Michael-Sanford/50a63ed8d073bf0f

I'm hard working, passionate about technology, and excellent at troubleshooting. I have 17 years of IT experience working tier 3 support for both manufacturing and office environments. For the last 3 years I have been serving as the Director of IT for Northwest Cascade. I am also serving on two advisory boards local to Washington State.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior IT Administrator / NOC Manager / Director of IT

Northwest Cascade Inc - Puyallup, WA -

September 2011 to Present

At Northwest Cascade I manage and oversee all computer and data related issues and vendor support contracts. I maintain all physical and virtual servers along with all backups and offsite backup solutions. I am the primary support for all PBX / VOIP related issues and configuration changes. I manage all LAN, WAN, MWAN, MPLS circuits (Fiber / T1 / T3 / POTS) BGP routing, QOS tags, and VLAN. I oversee all data center activities and projects and assign teams. I assist all application developers and deliver solutions for their needs. Manage all mobile devices and MDM solutions along with Apple DEP and VPP deployments and solutions. Travel to all sites once a year to asses IT computer needs and solutions. Manage all network devices related to "BIO Recycling" and EPA regulation requirements (PH Probe reports, Rain Tower and other Omega devices and reporting). Manage and work with PLC programmers to deliver automated system solutions Allen Bradley, Rockwell, and TSI Inc.

IT Intern / IT Administrator / Senior IT Administrator

Milgard Manufacturing Inc - Puyallup, WA -

July 2002 to September 2011

Milgard Manufacturing I started out as an Intern working at the corporate office. I quickly caught on and found what I loved in life "Technology" I worked in tier 1 help desk position for a year and was given a position serving as an Administrator for Pultrusion, a R&D division at the time for Milgard. Quickly after taking on Pultrusion I was given the brother division of this operation called Woodclad, which I managed and ran for four more years. Milgard was growing and so was the IT staff, the four local IT Guerue's at the time were asked to form a Milgard Corporate Senior IT staff where we led the Company to an eventual merger with MASCO Corporation. When I left Milgard Manufacturing I was one of three that managed all day to day operations and manufacturing processes for the six Milgard Manufacturing Buildings and Corporate offices.

EDUCATION

high school Mountain View High School - Mesa, AZ

1997

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)

June 2011 to Present

VM Partner

June 2015 to Present